占领华尔街
Takeover Wall street!
占领华尔街  占领华尔街
Takeover Wall street! Takeover Wall street!
要把后面的人群都拍进去  马克
Make sure you get the crowd in the background, Mark.
最后拍一次你和抗议人群的合影
Another shot of you and the chanting masses.
我再也不想来拍抗议了
I'm so over this protest.
下次我们去拍巴西T台模特  我保证
Next time we'll do a piece on Brazilian runway models, I promise.
说话算数
Gonna hold you to that.
好了  我们开拍吧
All right. Let's roll this puppy.
占领华尔街  占领华尔街
Takeover Wall street! Takeover Wall street!
收到
Roger that.
占领华尔街
Takeover Wall street!
击鼓帝  你影响音效了
Hey, ringo! You're messing up sound.
去别地方敲行不行
How about you take it somewhere else?
占领华尔街
Takeover Wall street!
好的  马上直播  三
Okay, live in three...
占领华尔街  占领华尔街
Takeover Wall street! Takeover Wall street!
占领华尔街
Takeover Wall street!
我现在在博亦伦广场
I'm here at Boylan Plaza
现在是占领抗议的第36天
on day 36 of the takeover protest.
不仅在此  全国各地都有数百人聚集
Hundreds have gathered here and in other cities across the country
抗议他们所谓的贪婪和腐败
to take a stand against what they say is greed and corruption.
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
如果你刚调到本频道
If you just tuned in,
刚刚发生了一起爆炸
there's been some kind of explosion
就在博亦伦广场的东南角上
on the southeast side of the Boylan Plaza.
我们尚不清楚爆炸起因和伤亡情况
We do not know what caused this or if there are injuries,
但是我能看到  似乎有人
but I can see what appear to be people
躺在地上  一动不动
on the ground, not moving.
真难以置信
This is unbelievable.
知道死亡人数吗
Any idea how many people were killed?
初步报告为五人死亡  28人受伤
Initial reports say five dead, 28 injured.
到处是联调局的人
There's Feds everywhere.
发生爆炸案  这是常规程序
Yeah, well, that's normal procedure in the event of a bomb.
这可绝不是常规事件
There's nothing normal about this.
探长  警方是否知道幕后黑手是谁
Detective, do the police know who's behind this?
警方是否怀疑这是恐怖袭击
Do they think this was a terrorist attack?
无可奉告  你们得去找新闻部
No comment. You'll have to deal with press relations.
-抱歉  请止步  -纽约警局的
- Oh, sorry. - NYPD.
纽约警局去那边
NYPD's over there.
联调局已接手犯罪现场的管辖权
FBI has taken jurisdiction of the crime scene.
多谢
Thanks.
走吧  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
联调局也把你们挡回来了  是吗
FBI turned you guys away, too, huh?
是啊  他们不让我们过警戒线
Yeah, they wouldn't let us past the crime scene tape.
怎么回事
What's going on?
盖茨在跟联调局交涉
Gates is talking to the Feds,
处理这个问题
trying to get a handle on that.
爆炸案有什么进展吗  谁引爆了炸弹
What do we know about the explosion, who set it off?
大概不是自杀爆炸
Well, it probably wasn't a suicide bomber.
我有个朋友是医务人员
I got a friend who's a medic,
说没在任何尸体上发现炸弹背心
said that there were no explosive vests on any of the bodies.
目前其他事还都是谣传
Everything else is just rumor at this point.
大伙儿听好了
Listen up, people.
我们还在拼凑事情经过
We're still piecing together what happened here.
但我能告诉大家  联调局和国土安全局
But what I can tell you-- FBI and Homeland Security
将负责本次调查
will be taking point on this investigation.
纽约警局将协助调查
NYPD will act in a support capacity.
我们首要任务
Our first assignment
是查明是否有哪个死者
is to determine if any of the victims
因为参与抗议而成为袭击目标
were targeted because of their involvement in the protest.
这会儿警员正在把亲属带往分局
Uniforms are bringing families to the precinct as we speak,
我们去安慰他们  做好本职工作吧
so... let's go hold some hands and do our jobs.
莱文先生
Mr. Levine,
据我所知  有位死者
I understand that one of the victims,
杰西·弗里德曼  生前跟你密切合作
Jesse Friedman, worked closely with you.
不止是合作
It was more than that.
他是我的朋友  我的战友
He was a friend, a comrade in arms, you know?
杰西负责招纳抗议者
Jesse was a recruiter.
几周前  参加抗议的人数减少时
When attendance dropped a few weeks back,
连我也以为该结束了
even I thought it was time to pack up,
但是杰西却引用了我最喜欢的名言
but Jesse just threw my favorite quote back at me.
就是那个沉默是罪恶
The one about sinning by silence.
"该抗议时  沉默即是罪恶
"To sin by silence when we should protest
沉默即是懦弱"
makes... cowards of men."
我们知道你现在一定很难过
We know that this is difficult,
但是你丈夫在占领活动中扮演什么角色
but what was your husband's involvement with the takeover movement?
马特没参与活动  我也没有
Matt wasn't involved. Neither am I.
那你们为什么会在博亦伦广场
So why were you at Boylan Plaza?
我们第一次来这儿
It's our first time here.
想尽量多看些地方
We wanted to take in as much as we could.
你们是游客
You're tourists?
我们刚刚登过帝国大厦的楼顶
We'd just been to the top of the Empire State Building.
还有点剩余的时间
We had an extra few minutes,
就决定去看看抗议活动是怎么回事
so we decided to see what the protest was all about.
马特和我刚刚买了房子
Matt and I just bought a house.
我们要建立一个家庭了
We were going to start a family.
我们都做了计划
We had all these plans.
我现在要怎么办
What am I gonna do now?
你没事吧
You good?
没事
Yeah, yeah.
就是这起案子
It's just this case, you know?
真让人难过
It kind of gets to you.
剩下几个家庭问的怎么样了
How'd it go with the rest of the families?
一个死者是家里第一个上大学的孩子
Um, one victim was the first kid in his family to go to college,
另一个是两个孩子的母亲
and the other was a mother of two, so...
你能想象得出
about like you'd expect.
不过似乎没有人是袭击目标
No one seems to have been targeted, though.
那么他们的死是偶然的了
So their deaths were random.
我们之前接触的大部分的被害人
You know, most of our victims, they...
他们的死都有原因
they die for a reason.
背后都有某种动机
You know, there's a logic behind it.
有时动机很扭曲
It's a twisted logic at times,
但好歹也能说得通
but... at least it makes some kind of sense.
但是这件案子
Yeah, but in this case,
这些人只是在错误的时间待在错误的地方
these people were just in the wrong place at the wrong time.
他们的未来和他们计划
And their future and all their plans,
伴随刹那的光亮灰飞烟灭
everything is just gone in a flash.
让人想到自己生命中的那些
It makes you think about all those things in your own life
不想再耽误下去的事情
that you don't want to put off anymore.
警监叫大家集合
Captain's gathering the troops.
现在看来这起袭击
Now that it appears that this attack
并不是针对任何一个人的
was not directed at any specific individual,
联调局给了我们新的任务
we've got a new assignment from the FBI.
我们都知道炸弹在哪爆炸
We all know where the bomb went off.
就在这儿  紧挨着这个街灯
It was here, right next to this lamppost.
联调局刚刚从一个抗议者的
The FBI just recovered this photo
手机里获取了这张照片
from a protester's cell phone.
是同一地点
It's of the same location,
拍摄时间是
taken 47 seconds...
爆炸前47秒
before the explosion.
这只说明一件事
That could only mean one thing.
炸弹是有人放在那里的
The bomb was placed here by someone
就在47秒的时间范围内
within our 47-second time period.
我们的任务是
Our task is to interview
逐一盘问博亦伦广场上的目击证人
all witnesses who were present at Boylan Plaza.
我们要找出任何看到爆炸之前
We are looking for anyone who saw what went on
街灯附近情况的人
by this lamppost before the blast.
长官  名单上有三百余人
Sir, there are over 300 names on this list.
我们要如何进行
How do you recommend that we proceed?
多叫些人手来
We bring in more shifts.
这些人中
Someone on that list
有人目睹了那47秒内炸弹被放在那儿
saw the bomb being planted within our 47-second window.
我们找到这人  就能找到炸弹客
We find that person, we find the bomber.
谢谢你的配合
Thank you for your time.
这真是毫无帮助
Well, that was unhelpful.
是啊  我看出其中的规律来了
Yeah. I'm starting to sense a pattern.
接下来这个女人声称
You know, this next woman says
她当时就在爆炸现场中心
that she was in the middle of the whole thing.
我们当时就在这
We were right here.
炸弹就像是在我们身边炸开似的
It's like the bomb went off right next to us.
"我们"是谁
Who's we?
我和我姐姐娜迪亚
Me and my sister Nadia.
她在外边等着呢
She's out there right now waiting.
用我去叫她吗
Should I go get her?
不用了  我们最好进行一对一的谈话
Uh, no, actually, it's better if we just talk one-on-one.
你们两个人参加抗议了吗
Now were the two of you participating in the protests?
我看起来像是劳苦大众吗
Do I look like I'm in the 99%?
没有  我们刚离开广场附近的婚礼精品店
No. We'd just left this bridal boutique near the plaza.
娜迪亚六月份结婚
Nadia's getting married in June.
你注意到街灯旁有人吗
And did you notice anyone standing near the light post?
没看见
I don't think so.
好的  请告诉我们
Okay, well, I'm gonna need you to tell us
炸弹爆炸之前你能回忆起来的一切
everything that you remember from just before the bombing,
从你当时的位置说起
starting with where you were.
我们当时在咖啡摊
We were at the coffee truck,
商量下一步去哪
just trying to figure out our next move.
我有点走不动了  娜迪亚
I'm a little shopped out, Nadia.
你试了整整11件婚纱
I mean, you tried on 11 dresses.
他们把我弄得像棉花糖巨怪似的
They made me look like a stay puft marshmallow.
我们还得继续逛
We have to keep looking.
我们不能回家上网找吗
Can we look from home online?
我才不在网上买我的婚纱呢
I'm not buying my wedding dress on the internet.
就是找点灵感  我们得重新部署
It's just to give us ideas. We need to regroup.
你离难缠新娘就差那么一步了
You are this close to Bridezilla territory.
或许结婚时我会穿牛仔裤
Oh, maybe I'll wear jeans to my wedding.
我们可以雇那个人当乐队
Maybe we can hire that guy as the band.
那是我的  还给我
That's mine! Give that back!
你能想象妈妈会是什么表情吗
Could you imagine the look on mom's--
靠
Damn it!
走路看道啊  这是我的
Watch where you're going. This is my--
爆炸的冲击力把我们俩都撞倒在地
The force of it knocked us on our asses.
娜迪亚差点被踩到
Nadia almost got trampled.
等等  你能重新说一下
Wait. Can you go back to the--
手拿盒子那个中东男人
The middle eastern man carrying the box.
你说他浑身是汗  而且很紧张
You said that he was sweaty and nervous?
他正往街灯方向走
And was he headed toward the lamppost?
是的
Yeah.
你还记得他长什么样吗  帮我们画个素描
Do you remember his face well enough to help us with a sketch?
西区瓦利
West Side Wally,
应群众的诚邀回归了
back by popular demand.
警察大哥  你知道我喜欢叫西区
Come on, Kojak. You know I prefer West Side.
好吧  就叫你西区
West Side then.
你在广场看过这个人吗
Uh, did you ever see that man at the plaza?
没有  不眼熟
No. Guy's not familiar.
每天见很多人  很多张脸
Then again, lots of people, lots of faces.
而且我在这里  那是我的老地方
Plus, I was over here. That's my usual spot.
不在咖啡摊旁  我不喜欢那味
Not by the coffee truck. I don't care for the smell.
你离炸弹爆炸地点有50米远
Well, that puts you 50 feet away from where the bomb went off.
你能清楚地看到这个街灯吗
Did you have a clear view of this lamppost?
看不到  伙计
Not really, man.
你知道我一直都很配合警方
And you know I always try to help Johnny Law.
在爆炸发生前的一分钟内
Did you notice anything out of the ordinary
你留意到任何异常情况吗
in the minute before the explosion?
或者是可疑的人
Anyone suspicious?
占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall street!
占领华尔街  占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall street! Takeover! Wall street!
事实上  还真有
As a matter of fact, I did.
占领华尔街  占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall street! Takeover! Wall street!
占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall street!
占领华尔街  占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall street! Takeover! Wall street!
准备好了
We're good to go.
打住
Stop.
让我理一理  你
Let me understand this. You...
你今天下午在广场
You saw beethoven,
看见死了两百多年的作曲家
the composer who's been dead for 200 years,
-贝多芬了  -是的
- in the plaza this afternoon? - Oh, yeah.
我打赌这半聋的混蛋
And I bet that half-deaf bastard
是这件事的幕后黑手
is behind all this.
西区  你现在服用什么药吗
West Side, are you on any medications of any kind?
这和这事有什么关系
I don't see how that's relevant.
你说没线索是什么意思
What do you mean, we have no leads?
那个中东男人又是怎么回事
What about the middle eastern man?
我们问过他了  他被排除嫌疑了
We interviewed him. He cleared.
他拿着的盒子里边都是中国外卖
Yeah, that box he was carrying-- full of chinese takeout.
那里面最危险的东西就是味精
Most dangerous thing in there was M.S.G.
事实上我们采访了94个人
Look, the fact is, is that we interviewed 94 people,
却毫无结果
and we've got nothing to show for it.
这不是我想要得到的结果
Uh, this is not the news I was hoping for,
尤其是联调局还送来了这个
especially since the FBI sent this over.
一个小时前  这封电邮被发往
It was e-mailed to two other takeover locations
纽约的另两处抗议地点
in New York an hour ago.
"已警告你们停止抗议
"You were warned to stop the protests.
你们不听
You didn't listen.
这回该听劝了
Start listening now
否则今天的爆炸将只是个开始"
or today's bombing will be just the beginning."
他还要袭击其他抗议活动
He's gonna hit another protest.
联调局已经封锁这条消息了
The FBI is keeping this one under wraps,
但是现在情况紧急
but the clock is still ticking here.
而且你们现在却告诉我
And what you're telling me
从炸弹爆炸到现在
is that we're no closer to getting this guy
我们在缉凶方面毫无进展
than we were when the bomb went off?
长官  这些人中有人目睹了
Sir, somebody on this list saw exactly what happened
那47秒内发生的一切
within that 47-second window.
但问题是  他们是混在
But the problem is, is that they're mixed in
那些什么都没看见的人中间
with all of these people that saw absolutely nothing.
这就像针海捞针一样
It's like trying to find Waldo in a sea of Waldos.
这么说你有解决这一问题的提议
I take it you have a proposal to fix that.
如果联调局能让我们看广场当时所有的录像带
If the FBI would let us view all video shot in the plaza,
或许我们就能发现谁离爆炸点最近
then maybe we can figure out who was closest to the bomb,
就能制定合理的盘问顺序
start prioritizing the interviews.
好的  我尽力去拿到录像带
Okay, I'll go down there, do my best.
如果那不管用  我们就得另寻他法
And if that doesn't work, we'll look to plan "B."
与此同时  继续按名单盘问
In the meantime, keep working on the list.
她似乎没多少把握能拿到录像带
She doesn't seem very optimistic about getting that footage.
要知道  离爆炸最近的目击者
You know, the witnesses that were closest to the bomb
不在我们的名单上
aren't on our list.
或许死人确实能说话
Maybe dead men do tell tales.
我刚刚在接待室看到一名记者
I just saw a reporter in reception.
让保安请他出去了
Have security get him outta here.
我不想让他打扰死者的家人
I don't want him bothering the victims' families.
看到亲切的面孔太好了
Oh! So nice to see a friendly face.
整晚都在跟联调局的人打交道
FBI has been up in mine all night.
这些都是爆炸案的被害人吗
All from the explosion?
他们毫无生还的希望
They never had a chance.
你如果想知道正式的死亡原因
If you're looking for official cause of death,
都是多重钝器创伤
it's multiple blunt force trauma.
其实我们想问  尸体上是否有什么线索
Actually, we were wondering if there's anything on the bodies
能帮我们抓到凶手
that might lead us to whoever did this.
有可能吧
Possibly.
这位是杰西·弗里德曼
Meet Jesse Friedman.
他负责为占领活动招纳抗议者
He was the recruiter for the takeover movement.
他也是离爆炸最近的一个人
He was also the guy closest to the blast.
我们发现很多这种东西嵌在他的皮肤里
And we found bits of this embedded all over his skin.
-蓝色纤维  -实验室鉴定为帆布
- Blue fabric? - The lab I.D.'ed it as canvas.
他们还在上面检测到高浓度的爆炸残留物
They also found high concentrations of explosive residue on it.
帆布是装炸弹的装置上的一部分
The canvas was part of whatever contained the bomb.
看起来是这样
Looks that way.
那就是粗呢包或者手提箱
So a duffel or a suitcase.
这真是很大的突破
This is a huge break.
这意味着凶手是拿蓝包的人
That means we're looking for someone carrying a blue bag.
我们去向盖茨警监汇报下进展
Let's go update Captain Gates.
你能等我一下吗
Uh, can you just give me a minute?
当然可以
Yeah, sure.
宝贝  你还好吗
Hey, honey. How you doing?
我没事  我想休息一下
Yeah, I just needed a minute.
你看起来很累
You look exhausted.
你在这儿待多久了
How long you been here?
我记不住了  这太乱了
I'm not sure. It's been so crazy.
我一直在编录死者的私人物品
I've been cataloging the victims' personal effects.
这让你很难过吧
Well, that can't be easy.
我一开始没事
I was fine.
直到我看见有个人带着一个手镯
Then I saw how one of them had on this bracelet--
就是小孩用玻璃珠串成的那种
a string with beads made by a little kid--
就像我6岁时  父亲节那天
and it--it was like that bracelet I made you
给你做的那个手镯
for father's day when I was 6.
还记得吗
Do you remember?
何止记得  我还留着呢
Remember? I still have it.
走吧  我送你回家
Come on. Let's get you home.
不  我还不能走  我还有工作要做
No, I should stay. There's still work to do.
明天干也行
And it'll be here tomorrow.
帕里什医生说必须赶在她...
Dr. Parish said I had to get all this finished before she--
蕾妮也会让你走的
Lanie will tell you the same thing.
快走吧
Let's get you outta here.
占领华尔街
Takeover Wall Street.
-好了  我们开拍吧  -收到
- All right. Let's roll this puppy. - Roger that.
这是本台记者琳安·韦斯特
That was our very own Leann West,
昨天正准备从博亦伦广场发来实况报道
about to report live from Boylan Plaza yesterday.
几秒过后  惨剧就发生了
Moments later, tragedy struck.
请注意  我们即将播出的部分画面
Be aware, some of the images we're about to show you
可能会令人不安
may be disturbing to some viewers.
不仅在此  全国各地都有数百人聚集
Hundreds have gathered here and in other cities across the country
抗议他们所谓的贪婪和腐败
to take a stand against what they say is greed and corruption--
我的天啊
Oh, my god.
到目前为止  本次爆炸案尚无嫌疑对象
So far no suspects have been named in the bombing.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
我的...
How's our...
我的孙女怎么样
How's our girl doing?
她在楼上睡觉呢
She's upstairs in bed, asleep.
我希望她能一直这么待着
I wish I could keep her in there.
亲爱的  你有没有想过
Honey, do you ever wonder
为什么你去分局工作的第一年
why I never visited you at the precinct
我从没去看过你
the first year you were working there?
我一直以为是因为那里灯光太闪眼
I always thought it was because of the harsh lighting.
那也算一个因素
Well, that was a consideration.
不  我之前觉得如果我看到你
No, I thought if I-- if I saw you
执行公务
acting like a cop,
我就会开始把你当警察看
I'd start thinking of you as a cop,
那我就...
and I just...
那我就会做各种噩梦
that--that brought on all manner of nightmares.
你是怎么克服的
How did you get over it?
最后  你意识到
Eventually, you realize,
你的孩子们会做你不喜欢的决定
your children are gonna make choices you don't like.
这是无法改变的事实
Just a fact of life.
如果说这次爆炸证明了什么
Well, if the bombing proves anything,
那就是不管你做什么  不幸都可能发生
it's that bad things can happen no matter what you do.
天有不测风云
Nobody's tomorrow is guaranteed.
那...你觉悟后有什么实际打算呢
So... How do you plan to act on this realization?
-什么意思  -你明白我的意思
- What do you mean? - Oh, you know what I mean.
理查德  你还想再拖多久
Richard, how much longer are you gonna drag your heels
才肯向贝克特表白
before you tell Beckett how you feel?
而且我的意思是趁她还清醒  而不是在胸部中枪
And I mean while she is awake, not lying on the ground
躺在地上的时候
with a bullet in her chest.
你不明白
You don't understand--
我知道你会说情况复杂
It's complicated, so you say.
可完全相反
Only it's not.
其实很简单
It's not.
天有不测风云  是吧
Nobody's tomorrows are guaranteed, right?
你为什么不去表白呢
Wouldn't it be better to tell her
即便时机不对
even if the timing is wrong
也好过永远没机会说出口
than never to tell her at all?
那如果她没准备好呢
And what if she isn't ready?
那她就永远不会给你机会了
Then she never will be.
那你就该释怀了
Then you move on.
谢了
Hey. Thanks.
没事  有空吗
Yeah. You got a sec?
有  什么事
Yeah. What's up?
我一直想
I've been thinking...
这些被害人们  还有...
about the victims and...
他们永远失去了的机会...
all the opportunities they'll never have...
而我不想也错过机会
and I don't want that to happen.
我一直...
I've been...
有线索
We got something.
没事  可以等到结案后再说
It's okay. It can wait till after the case.
拿到广场的录像了吗
Did you get the video from the plaza?
还没  不过我掌握的线索更有用
Not yet, but what I have here is even better.
无线运营商的数据
Data from wireless carriers
显示了博亦伦广场上所有启动了GPS的手机
that shows us all the GPS-activated cell phones in Boylan Plaza.
这是昨天下午4点32分广场的情况
This is the plaza yesterday at 4:32,
就在爆炸发生前
right before the explosion.
每个红点代表的是一部特定手机GPS位置
Each red dot represents the GPS position of a specific phone.
你怎么拿到的
How did you get this?
我找了国土安全局的一个朋友帮忙要来的
I called in a favor from a friend at Homeland Security.
真是个好朋友
That is a damn good friend.
那如果那些红点代表的是手机
So then if those red dots represent cell phones,
那我们能查出机主吗
can we figure out who they belong to?
就是这个目的
That's the whole idea.
如果这图显示了离炸弹最近的人
If this shows us who was closest to the bomb,
就能确定目击证人了
it gives us our witnesses.
还能显示每个人的实时地点
It can even show us where everyone was in real time.
快进到4点32分
Advance it to 4:32.
你试了整整11件婚纱
I mean, you tried on 11 dresses.
他们所谓的贪婪和腐败...
what they say is greed and corruption--
那些点消失了
the dots that disappeared,
那是爆炸发生的时间
That's the explosion.
等等  你们看到了吗
Wait a second. You guys see that?
就在...
There was--
爆炸发生前
right before the bomb went off.
莱恩  能倒退十秒吗
Ryan, could you take it back ten seconds?
看那个点
That dot right there.
就在爆炸发生前
Right before the explosion,
它跑去了爆炸发生点
it goes to the blast site,
逗留了一秒
waits for a second,
然后迅速跑开了
and then rushes away.
重放一遍
Play it again.
你试了整整11件婚纱
I mean, you tried on 11 dresses.
那是炸弹客
That's the bomber.
我把他的身份信息调出来
So I'm gonna to pull up his I.D.
手机登记在安德鲁·海耶斯名下
Cell phone's registered to an Andrew Haynes.
告诉我他现在的所在地
Tell me where he is right now.
没有GPS信号
No GPS signal.
要么是电池没电  要么是关机了
Uh, his battery's either dead or his phone is off.
等等  海耶斯这名字很耳熟
Wait a minute. Haynes sounds familiar.
他二十分钟前刚来分局做笔录
He showed up in the precinct 20 minutes ago for an interview.
炸弹客在楼里
The bomber's in the building?
警员对他进行了全身搜查
Unis gave him a full body.
没武器  没爆炸物
No weapons. No explosives.
他还以为他是作为目击者来接受问询吗
He still thinks he's here as a witness?
我们告诉他搜身是例行公事
We told him the search was routine.
这就是安德鲁·海耶斯
So this is Andrew Haynes.
他什么背景
What's his story?
他反对占领活动
He has it out for the takeover Movement.
他组织过反示威
He's organized counterdemonstrations,
破坏他们的集会  还发过传单
disrupted their rallies, he's even handed out fliers
说应采取任何必要手段阻止那些抗议者
saying how they should be stopped by any means necessary.
他还付诸了行动  他还是几年前
He walks the walk, too. He was a suspect in the bombing
一些绿色和平组织办事处爆炸案的疑犯
of some Greenpeace offices a few years back.
他的住处有发现吗
Anything turn up at his place?
有  证据确凿
Yeah, a smoking gun.
警员发现了他常去的网络咖啡屋的收据
Unis found receipts to an internet cafe where he goes.
他们追踪那些恐吓邮件
Now they traced those e-mail threats
查到了那间咖啡馆和海耶斯的登陆账号
back to that cafe and Haynes log-in I.D.
他就是我们要找的人
He's our guy.
那他为什么还能在这里走来走去  镇定自若
So then why is he strolling in here just as cool as could be?
我猜  他对他的所作所为很自豪
My guess-- he's proud of what he's done,
迫不及待要告诉别人
can't wait to tell someone about it.
那我们就给他机会  让他如愿以偿
Well, then let's give him the opportunity to do just that.
你好  海耶斯先生
Hi, Mr. Haynes.
我是凯特·贝克特探长
I'm Detective Kate Beckett.
非常感谢你前来配合调查
Thank you so much for coming in.
你们也该找我来了
It's about time you brought me in here.
要是让我跟那些唧唧歪歪的麻烦精挤在一起
If I had to rub elbows with those whiny little troublemakers...
我可能要动粗了
I was gonna do something drastic.
是啊  我可不会怪你
Oh, yeah, well, I wouldn't blame you.
你思想自由  我深表敬意
Hey, free thinker. I respect that.
撇开我的个人意见
Um, you know, my personal feelings aside,
我还是得调查这个案件
I still have to investigate this incident.
当然  工作时得一丝不苟嘛
Yeah, you know, you--you gotta dot your I's, cross your t's.
我懂
I get that.
没错  我得问你几个问题
Exactly. So I just have to ask you a few questions
关于爆炸发生之前你都看到了什么
about what you saw just before the bombing,
先说说...
starting with...
你当时的位置吧
where you were.
我  我当时...
I, uh, I-I was...
差不多  就在这儿
I was, like, right up here.
也就是说
Um, so that's
-在距离爆炸点三十米左右的地方吗  -对
- about 100 feet from the blast site? - Yeah.
你当时在干嘛
And what were you doing there?
我就是在跟他们争论
Oh, I was, uh, pretty much getting hassled.
愣小子  长长见识吧
Hey, nimrod. Here. Educate yourself.
拿着  好好看看吧
Here. Why don't you give this a read?
嘿  幼齿大叔
Hey, garanimal pants.
少在这儿求同情了  找份工作吧
Quit the pity party. Get a freakin' job.
自力更生你懂不懂  喂
Pull yourself up by your bootstraps. Hello.
嘿  我跟你说话呢
Hey! I'm talking to you.
小子  你能
Kitten, can you take--
你干嘛
What's your problem?
-你不爽我说的话吗  -对不起
- You don't like what I have to say? - Sorry.
没法面对现实吗
Huh? Can't face the truth?
不好意思  我要问明白
I'm sorry. Just--just so I'm clear, so...
你爆炸发生前一直在跟抗议者争辩吗
you were debating with the protesters until that bomb went off?
没错  我想让他们面对现实
Yeah, I was trying to give 'em a reality check.
他们在那儿竭力抗议什么贪婪的公司
I mean, you know, they're all up in arms about the greedy corporation,
可也不想想是谁给他们提供的工作
and who do they think is creating the jobs?
这帮人是吃饱了撑得伪君子罢了
You know, they're a bunch of silver-spoon hypocrites.
半数人甚至都
I mean, half of them, they don't--
不知道自己在抗议什么东西
they don't even know who they're protesting against.
没错  阻止他们其实是给国家造福了
Right, and stopping them would actually be a service to this country.
对  真心爱国的人都会把这视为当务之急
Yeah, it'd be item number one on any true patriot's to-do list.
你是一名真正的爱国者  对不对
And you are a true patriot, aren't you,
-安德鲁  -一点儿没错
- Andrew? You're damn right about that.
所以为了你爱的国家
That's why you put that bomb in the Plaza,
你就在广场上放置了那个炸弹
to defend the country that you love?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
得了吧  安德鲁
Come on, Andrew.
我不想你坐没必要坐的牢
I don't want you to have to serve any more time than you have to.
你跟那些抗议者意见相左
We know that you weren't with those protesters.
于是你来到这里  放下炸弹
You were down here, dropping off the bomb
-然后跑开躲起来  -有什么证据
-and then running for cover. -Based on what?
我们追查了你的手机
We traced your phone.
GPS显示你就在那
The GPS places you right there.
你不能证明那是我  我手机昨天丢了
You can't prove it was me. I lost my phone yesterday.
是吗
Really?
好吧  那你给我解释下这个
Okay, then maybe you can explain this.
你在网络咖啡屋发的恐吓信
Threatening e-mails that you sent from an internet cafe,
声称抗议活动不停止你就要继续制造爆炸
promising to continue those bombings until the protests stopped.
我要求跟我的律师谈
I'd like to talk to my lawyer.
白人男性
White male,
反社会的不合群者  有极端政治观点
antisocial loner, extreme political views--
跟行为科学部给我们提供的罪犯特征完全吻合
he's a perfect fit for the profile B.S.U. worked up for us.
我们会把他带到市里继续审问的
We'll continue questioning him downtown.
可我的手下说他并不认罪
Well, according to my people, he's nowhere near confessing.
让他们对目击者进行回访
Well, have them reinterview the witnesses
找到目睹了海耶斯把背包放下的目击者
and find us someone that saw Haynes put that backpack down.
不用谢
You're welcome.
我们根据GPS找到二十名目击海耶斯走过的人
So we talked to 20 witnesses along Haynes' GPS path,
但没有人能准确地认出他
but none of them can positively I.D. Him.
当时太乱  没人能够肯定到底发生了什么
With all the confusion, no one's exactly sure what happened.
你们有查到什么没
You guys have any luck?
四个人称看到过一个穿黑色占领活动套头衫的人
Four people remember seeing a guy in a black Takeover hoodie,
可没人看到他的长相
but nobody remembers seeing his face.
一件黑色套头衫可不足以结案
A black hoodie doesn't get us home,
半数抗议者都穿着一样的衣服
not with half the protesters wearing them.
肯定有人见过这家伙
Somebody had to have seen this guy.
我们还漏掉了一名抗议者
There's a protester we haven't spoken to yet--
那个街头鼓手
The street drummer.
摄影师赶走他之后
After the cameraman rousted him,
那个伴娘说他走到
that bridesmaid said he relocated...
咖啡摊附近了
by the coffee truck,
那么他也该看到海耶斯走过
which would put him right in Haynes' path.
也就是说他有可能看到了海耶斯的脸
Which means he could've seen Haynes' face.
没错  可我们不知道他的名字
Yeah, but we don't know his name
他不在目击者名单上
and he's not on our witness list.
我们要怎么找到他
How are we gonna find this guy?
他是个街头表演者
You know what? He's a street performer.
有可能因滋扰行为收到过法院传票
He's probably gotten nuisance citations, which means,
如果真有  那我们应该就能找到他
if he has, we should be able to I.D. Him.
我是做音乐的  干嘛逮捕我
I make music. Why do you arrest me?
我们不是逮捕你  马利克
We're not arresting you, Malik.
只不过想问你几个问题而已
We just need to ask you a few questions
昨天下午你在博亦伦广场都看到了什么
about what you saw in Boylan Plaza yesterday afternoon.
我对爆炸的事一无所知
I know nothing about the bomb.
-我是无辜的  -我们相信你
- I am an innocent man. - And we believe you.
但你有可能看到了什么
But we think that you might have seen something
能够帮我们抓到凶手
that'll help us catch the person who did this.
我  我不想惹麻烦
I-I don't want trouble.
马利克  你的护照是不是过期了
Malik, your visa expired, didn't it?
所以你才这么焦虑  是吗
Is that what's worrying you?
我不能回自己的国家去
I cannot go back to my country.
我不会把你遣送回去的
And I won't make you.
我不管你是不是非法滞留
I don't care about your immigration status.
我们只想知道
We just need to know
爆炸发生之前你都看到了什么
exactly what you saw just before that explosion.
我会把记得的都告诉你们
I will tell you what I can.
好的
Okay.
你在咖啡摊旁表演的时候
When you were playing by the coffee truck,
有个男的穿着占领活动运动衫走过你旁边
a man walked by you wearing a black Takeover Sweatshirt.
你记得他吗
Do you remember seeing him?
没错  我看到过
Yes. I saw him.
等等  你是说
Wait a minute. Are you saying
你看到身穿占领活动运动衫的男人
that you saw the man wearing the Takeover Sweatshirt
在街灯前放下了一个蓝色背包吗
put down a blue backpack in front of the lamppost?
-没错  -你看到他的脸没
- Yes. - Did you get a good look at his face?
靠
Damn it!
你确定你看到的那个放包的男人
You're certain the man you saw leaving the backpack
是二十多岁的西班牙人吗
was Hispanic and in his 20s?
确定
Yes.
我  我说的不对吗
I-I gave the wrong answer?
你确定不是这个人
Are you sure this wasn't the person?
确定  不是他
No. That's not him.
联调局抓错人了
The FBI has got the wrong guy.
也就是说真正的炸弹客还逍遥法外
Which means the real bomber is still out there.
如果炸弹不是安德鲁·海耶斯放的
If Andrew Haynes didn't plant the bomb,
为什么他要发那些恐吓信
then why did he e-mail those threats?
为什么GPS显示他逃离了犯罪现场
Why does his GPS show him fleeing the scene?
目前我们无从得知
We can't answer that yet,
不过目击者给了我们一张精确的画像
but our witness gave a good description.
就是这个人
It was this man.
我们怎么知道这人没在瞎编
How do we know this guy is not making this up?
有关爆炸案的详情
Look, the details of the bomb
还没有公布给媒体
haven't been released to the press yet,
除非目击者亲眼见到那个蓝色背包
so how would our witness know about the blue backpack
不然他从何得知
unless he actually saw it?
好吧  你们就追查这条线索
All right, you people pursue this.
看看能有什么结果
see where it leads.
但是安德鲁·海耶斯仍是我们的头号嫌犯
But Andrew Haynes is still our prime suspect.
至少在你们找到比街头音乐家更
At least until you can give me something more
可靠的证词之前
than the word of a street musician.
找到这个人
Identifying this man,
这是我们现在的首要任务
that is now our top priority.
根据证词
According to our witness,
案发时他身着占领活动运动衫
he was wearing a Takeover Sweatshirt,
因此他可能是名抗议者
so he might be part of the movement.
把这张素描分发下去  询问其他抗议者
Show this sketch around, talk to other protesters.
如果他是博亦伦广场的常客
If he was a regular in Boylan Plaza,
肯定就会有人认出他
someone there must know who he is.
卡塞尔先生  你就别去了
Uh, not you, Mr. Castle.
我有项特别任务交给你
I have a special task for you.
我听说你一目十行
I hear that you're quite the speed reader,
而且在我认识你的这段时间里
and in the time that I've known you,
你有时...
you've shown, well...
表现出对细节的超常洞察力
on occasion, an exceptional attention to detail.
这是你第一次对我大加赞...
That's the first time you've ever paid me a complime--
继续
Go on.
目前我们已进行了上百次的笔录
We've conducted over a hundred interviews so far,
需要有个人快速审阅一遍
And someone needs to review them swiftly,
查找能锁定嫌疑人的线索
looking for information that can help us I.D. Our suspect.
我相信你是我最好的人选
And, uh, I believe, you're my best bet.
我想她终于开始喜欢我了
I think she's finally starting to like me.
我可没有
No, I'm not.
烦死她
Wearing her down.
-早上好  -早啊
-Good morning. -Morning.
案子有什么进展吗
Any breaks in the case?
没有  我在研究这些目击者证词
No. I've been poring over these witness statements
查找炸弹客的线索
looking for clues about our bomber,
但是目前为止  一无所获
but so far, nothing.
也许吃点这个会带给你好运
Well, maybe these will bring you some luck.
这是突发事件的庆祝煎饼
These are emergency cheering-up pancakes.
我是说  通常都是为闹僵之后
I mean, these are usually reserved for after breakups
或是《与星共舞》的淘汰赛准备的
or "Dancing With the Stars" eliminations.
-这次是什么缘由  -那天之后
- What's the occasion? - Well, after the other day,
我想我们俩都需要打起精神
I thought we both needed some cheering up.
你本不需要打起精神
You shouldn't need cheering up.
你就不该在那儿
You shouldn't have even been there.
你本该跟朋友待在一起  或是看电影
You should've been with your friends or at the movies.
-爸  我18岁了  -我知道
- Dad, I'm 18. - I know.
我知道  只是...
I know. It's just...
你还会看到许多残酷的现实
You're gonna see plenty of reality in your lifetime.
我只想让你这眼镜上的玫瑰色
I just would like you to keep the rose color on your glasses
保持得越久越好
for as long as possible.
爸  我并没有盯住丑恶的一面
But I'm trying not to focus on the ugly side of it, dad.
我已经得到了全A
I-I've gotten straight a's,
各种奖励  奖杯多得我都数不过来了
awards, more trophies than I can count.
这份工作让我第一次
This job is the first thing
感到自己在做重要的事
that's made me feel like I'm doing something important,
有价值的事
valuable.
你干这一行不也是这个原因吗
I mean, isn't that why you do it?
你是个相当聪明的孩子  你知道吗
You're a pretty smart kid, you know that?
这么嘛
Well...
人们都说  天才...
They say genius...
都是隔代遗传的
skips a generation.
很显然  风趣也是
Apparently, so does funny.
吃你的煎薄饼吧
Eat your pancake.
好吧
Right.
怎么回事
What's going on?
没什么  我只是在想下一步行动
Um, nothing. I'm just thinking about my next move.
我可能替你想好了
I may have it for you.
我们找到这个人的线索
We got a line on this guy.
有人认出了素描
Someone I.D.'ed the sketch?
对  一个名叫詹尼·克莱恩的示威者
Yeah, a protester named Jenni Klein,
说她认识这个人叫鲍比
Says she knows this guy as Bobby.
没有姓吗
And there's no last name?
没有  但这个鲍比有次邀请她去过家里
No, but this bobby invited her over once.
她知道他住哪
She knows where he lives.
你好  鲍比
Hey, Bobby.
脱下背包
Remove the backpack
慢慢把它放在地上
And place it on the ground, slowly.
然后跪下
Then get on your knees.
只是一些运动衣和几瓶水
Just a bunch of gym clothes and some water bottles.
跟上次不一样对吧  鲍比
Not like last time, huh, bobby?
起来
Get up.
罗伯特·洛佩兹
Robert Lopez.
这是你的名字
That's your name.
对吗  鲍比
Right, Bobby?
其实  我对你很了解
Actually, I know quite a bit about you.
我知道你的住所
I know where you live.
我知道你没有案底
I know you don't have a record.
我知道你没加入任何政治派别
I know you're not a member of any political party.
等我的团队搜完你家
And as soon as my team finishes searching your place,
我会知道得更多
I'm gonna know even more.
反正我终究会查出来
So eventually, I'll find out,
你还不如直接跟我坦白
but why don't you just tell me?
你为什么要安置那颗炸药
Why did you plant that bomb?
那些目击者证词  毫无发现
Hey. No luck with those witness statements.
你们找到线索了吗
You guys catch a break?
比那还好  我们抓到嫌疑人了
Better yet, we caught the suspect.
而我错过了  他在哪
And I missed it? Where is he?
贝克特在问话
In the box with Beckett.
想让我帮你回忆回忆吗
Would you like me to refresh your memory?
你当时站在这个路灯柱边
You were standing here by the lamppost.
扔下了背包
You dropped the backpack
然后赶紧跑开  炸弹爆炸了
and then you started running as it exploded
五人被害
and killed five people.
我没有  你说的事我没做过
I didn't--I didn't do what you're saying.
鲍比  有目击者看到你扔下背包
Witnesses saw you drop your backpack, Bobby.
那不是我的
It wasn't mine.
那你承认你当时拿着它了
Oh, so you admit to having it?
不  我不是这个意思
No. That's--that's not what I meant.
你刚才说那不是你的
You just said that it wasn't yours.
没错  因为你把我弄糊涂了
Yeah, because you got me all confused--
你到底有没有拿着它
Did you or didn't you have it?
这个问题很简单
It's a simple question.
我不知道
I don't know.
是谁指使你这么做的  鲍比
Who put you up to this, Bobby?
谁把背包给你的
Who gave you that backpack?
我不  我不知道  我不记得了
I don't--I don't know. I don't remember.
你不记得了  你怎么会不记得
You don't remember? How do you not remember?
我当时吓坏了
I was in shock.
炸弹爆炸了  所有人都边喊边叫
The bomb went off. Everyone was running and screaming--
好了好了  你记得炸弹爆炸后
Oh, okay, okay, so remember what happened
发生的事  之前的却忘了
after the bomb went off, but not before.
我一定是得了创伤后失忆症之类的
It must have been one of those traumatic amnesia things.
鲍比  别跟我撒谎
Bobby... Don't lie to me.
我是在告诉你  当时一片空白
I'm telling you, it was all a big blank.
是因为创伤所致
It was the trauma.
跟创伤无关
It was not the trauma.
你不准那个借口
You don't get to use that excuse.
我发誓  我不记得了
I swear, I don't remember.
去你的不记得了
The hell you don't remember.
你想了解创伤吗
Do you want to know trauma?
我胸部中过枪  而事情经过的分分秒秒
I was shot in the chest and I remember
我都记得
every second of it.
所以你也会记得
And so do you.
这么久以来
All this time...
你都记得
you remembered?
那家伙还是没招
Guy's still not talking?
还没  我让他一个人出出冷汗
Not yet. I'm gonna let him sweat for a bit.
卡塞尔来了吗
Was Castle here?
对  来了
Yeah, earlier.
但又说得走了
But he said he had to go.
说要去个地方
Said there was somewhere he needed to be.
理查德  搞什么
Oh, Richard...really?
炸弹事件追悼会
A bomb memorial?
拜托  宝贝  这不是有点变态啊
Come on, honey. Isn't this kind of morbid?
这正是我现在的感受
Well, it's how I'm feeling.
她又没死
She isn't dead.
她倒不如死了
She might as well be.
我真以为我们能一起有未来
I really thought we could have a future together.
我愿意等她
You know, I was-- I was willing to wait.
结果发现一切不过是天大的玩笑
Come to find out it was just a big joke.
她都知道
She knew.
都这么久了  她都记得
This whole time, she remembered,
而她一字不提
and she didn't say anything...
因为她很尴尬
Because she was embarrassed
因为她不爱我
Because she doesn't feel the same way.
我真蠢
I'm such a fool.
好了  我们回家吧
Well, come on. Let's go home.
开瓶好酒
Break out some of the good stuff, okay?
我倒是想  我得回去
Oh, I'd love to. I gotta be getting back.
回去
Back?
你明知她心里的想法  明知她喜欢过你
Why on earth would you go back
你究竟为什么回去
knowing how she feels, knowing that she liked you--
不是为了她  这是...
This isn't about her. This is...
这是为了他们
This is about them.
这是为了做实事
You know it's about doing something real...
重要的事
something that matters.
我不愿意放弃
I'm not willing to let that go.
理查德  爱情不是开关
Richard, love is not a switch.
你没法说关就关
You can't just turn it off.
你不可能和她并肩工作而不心动
You can't work side by side with her and not feel anything.
看我的吧
Watch me.
你刚才去哪儿了
Hey. Where were you?
就是去清醒一下  对鲍比的调查进展如何
Just clearing my head. Where are we on Bobby?
警员们正在搜查他的住所
Uniforms are searching his place.
我们希望能找到些证据  让他松口
We're hoping to find something that'll break him.
联调局打电话来提供了跟进情况
FBI called with an update.
博亦伦广场引爆的炸弹
The device used in Boylan Plaza
是管状炸药  蹊跷之处在于
was a pipe bomb, here's the weird part,
它没有加置钉子等任何东西
it wasn't packed with nails or anything else
的确很蹊跷  凶手一般会加置发射物
That is weird, bombers usually add projectiles
以提高杀伤力
to maximize damage.
那可不是提高杀伤力的唯一方法
That's not the only way to maximize damage.
它是由什么引爆的
So what was it triggered by,
手机引爆还是触发式
cell phone, trip wire?
是远程控制  可能是用车库门遥控开关改装的
A remote, probably rigged from a garage door opener.
但控制范围只有大约30米
But the range of those was only about 100 feet
所以引爆炸药的人当时一定身处博亦伦广场
So whoever detonated it was in Boylan Plaza.
我打赌你能在鲍比的住所内
And I bet you will find that garage remote
找到那个车库门遥控器
in Bobby's apartment.
没那么好的运气
Uh, no such luck. But...
不过我们找到一堆信用卡
we did find credit cards
上面写着许多不同人的姓名
with lots of different names on them.
我们还找到一些钱包
And we found some wallets
和几部手机
and some cell phones, too.
而且  其中一部手机
In fact, one of those cell phones
是属于安德鲁·海耶斯的
belonged to Andrew Haynes.
鲍比是名扒手
Bobby's a pickpocket.
是的  你可以这么说
Yeah, I pretty much am.
这就是你参加占领活动的原因  为偷窃
That's why you attended the Takeover! Protests?
那么多人聚在一起
All those people hanging out,
各种和谐  各种友爱
full of peace and brotherhood...
占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street!
占领华尔街  华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street! Wall Street,
-我们要做什么  -占领华尔街
- What do we want? - Takeover! Wall Street!
愣小子  长长见识吧
Hey, Nimrod. Here. Educate yourself.
给你  长长见识
Here. Educate--
占领华尔街  占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street! Takeover! Wall Street!
就像是扒手的天堂
Like an all-you-can-steal buffet.
你懂的
You got that right.
你为何一开始不告诉我们真相
Why didn't you just tell me the truth from the start?
怎么  向怀疑我谋杀的警察
And what, admit to a cop that likes me for murder
承认自己是扒手吗
that I'm a thief?
-谎称失忆似乎更靠谱些吧  -是啊
- Amnesia seemed like the better plan. - Yeah.
那么说你顺走了安德鲁·海耶斯的手机
So you lifted Andrew Haynes' phone,
使我们误以为是他安置的炸弹
which is why it looked as if he planted the bomb.
谁是安德鲁·海耶斯
Who's Andrew Haynes?
不关你的事
Don't worry about that.
跟我说说背包是怎么回事
Talk to me about the backpack.
你是如何拿到它的
How did you get it?
懂吗  你们这些人  你们是病毒
You know, you people, you're a virus.
你们不负责任
You're irresponsible.
你们在毒害这个国家
You're infecting this country.
你好  你能听到吗
Hello. Can you hear?
你可能听不到...你能说英语吗
You probably couldn't hear your--do you hablas English?
我顺走了它
I lifted it.
它就躺在两个垃圾桶之间
It was just lying there between two dumpsters.
嘿  别动  那是我的
Hey! Hey, that's mine.
还给我  那是我的  还给我
Give me that. That's mine! Give that back.
嘿  那是我的包
Hey! Hey, hey, that's my bag.
占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street!
-给我回来  -占领华尔街  占领华尔街
- Come back! - Takeover! Wall Street! Takeover! Wall Street!
给我回来  嘿  你给我回来
Come back here. Hey, hey, you.
你离难缠新娘就差那么一步了
...this close to bridezilla territory.
或许结婚时我会穿牛仔裤
Oh, maybe I'll wear jeans to my wedding.
我们可以雇那个人当乐队
Maybe we can hire that guy as the band.
靠
Damn it!
我发誓
I swear, I...
我不知道里面有炸弹
I didn't know a bomb was in it.
我不想伤害任何人
I would never hurt anyone.
你们得相信我
Look, you gotta believe me.
那个声称被偷背包的人
The man who said that you took his backpack,
是他吗
Is that him?
是的  就是这家伙
Yeah. That--that's-- that's the guy.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
是的
Yeah.
是的  就是他
Yeah, that's him.
那是杰西·弗里德曼
That's Jesse Friedman.
他是被害人之一
He's one of the victims.
而且他还是抗议活动的成员之一
And he's a member of the movement.
这说不通啊
That doesn't make any sense.
他为什么要袭击自己人
Why would he attack his own people?
好的  谢谢你
Okay. Thank you.
警员们搜查了杰西·弗里德曼的住所
So unis searched Jesse Friedman's place.
他们发现了研制
and they found research on how to build
与博亦伦广场相同炸弹装置的研究
the same device that was used in Boylan Plaza.
难道说杰西毁掉了自己的抗议活动
So Jesse blew up his own protest?
他为何要那样做
Why would he do that?
也许是想赢得公众们对他抗议活动的同情吧
Maybe to get sympathy for his movement, publicity--
而且由于他把炸弹安置在两个垃圾桶之间
and since he placed the bomb between two dumpsters...
他没料到会有人受伤
He didn't think that anyone would get hurt.
直到鲍比偷走了他的背包
Then Bobby stole the backpack.
如果杰西担心有人受伤
If Jesse was worried about someone getting hurt,
他为何还要引爆炸弹
why would he set off the bomb?
我认为不是他引爆的
I don't think he did.
他尸体附近没有发现遥控装置
There was no remote found on or near the body,
说明引爆者另有他人
which means someone else detonated it.
也许是他认识的人
Probably somebody he knew.
炸弹爆炸前30秒
30 seconds before the blast,
杰西接到一个由一次性手机打来的电话
Jesse got a call on his cell from a burner phone.
炸弹爆炸前20秒
Then two seconds before the bomb went off,
他试图回拨那个号码
He tried to call that same phone back.
所以杰西也许有个同伙
So then maybe Jesse had a partner,
就是那人引爆了炸弹
and that's who triggered the bomb.
你曾说遥控装置只有30米的有效范围  是吧
You said that remote had a range of about 100 feet, right?
所以无论他的同伙是谁
So whoever the partner was,
他一定在这附近
he must have been here somewhere,
靠近炸弹的引爆点
close to the bomb blast,
隐匿在人群中
hidden among the crowd.
我们得重新梳理一下事件顺序
We need to take another look at the sequence of events,
把目击者的证词整合起来
piece together the witness statements.
答案将自在其中
The answer is in the story.
我们从头开始
So let's start at the beginning.
占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street!
占领华尔街  占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street! Takeover! Wall Street!
琳安和她的摄像师正在准备
Leann and her cameraman are setting up
他们的现场直播
for their live broadcast.
要把后面的人群都拍进去  马克
Be sure you get the crowd in the background, Mark.
最后拍你一次你和抗议人群的合影
Another shot of you and the chanting masses.
我再也不想来拍抗议了
I'm so over this protest.
下次我们去拍巴西T台模特  我保证
Next time we'll do a piece on brazilian runway models, I promise.
说话算数
Gonna hold you to that.
好了  我们开拍吧
All right. Let's roll this puppy.
占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street!
收到
Roger that.
与此同时
At the same time,
鲍比在广场上徘徊
Bobby's prowling the plaza.
他看到安德鲁·海耶斯正对示威者们高谈阔论
He sees Andrew Haynes haranguing the protesters.
少在这儿求同情了
Quit the pity party.
自力更生你懂不懂
Pull yourself up by the bootstraps.
愣小子  长长见识吧
Hey, Nimrod. Here. Educate yourself.
拿着  好好看看吧
Here, why don't you give this a read?
嘿  幼齿大叔
Hey, garanimal pants.
他很容易下手
He's easy pickings.
给你  长...
Here, educ--
就这样  鲍比偷走了他的手机
So Bobby relieves him of his phone.
占领华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street!
长长见识吧
Educate yourself, would you?
接着  鲍比继续寻找下一个"商机"
Then Bobby goes looking for his next business opportunity.
他发现了无人看管的蓝色背包
He spots the blue backpack unattended,
向他呼唤
calling out to him.
他拿起那个背包
So he grabs it,
欣喜若狂而没有意识到包里面装的是什么
blissfully unaware of what's inside.
包是我的
Hey! Hey, that's mine.
但杰西看到后失控了
But Jesse sees him and he flips out.
还给我  包是我的
Give me that. That's mine!
把包还给我
Give that back!
嘿  嘿  包是我的
Hey! Hey! That's mine!
鲍比消失在人群中  杰西慌了
Bobby ducks out of sight. Jesse panics.
炸弹在移动
The bomb is on the move.
他会怎么做呢
What's he gonna do?
人们身处危险之中
People are in danger.
他抓住一个穿着黑色连帽衫的人
He grabs a man in a black hoodie,
以为他就是小偷
thinking it's the thief.
你干嘛
What's your problem?
-你不爽我说的话吗  -对不起
- You don't like what I have to say? - Sorry.
没法面对现实吗
Huh? Can't face the truth?
那人就是安德鲁·海耶斯
But it's Andrew Haynes.
接管华尔街  接管华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street! Takeover! Wall Street!
这时  鲍比意识到
But by now, Bobby's decided
提着背包并不明智
taking the backpack wasn't such a good idea.
接管华尔街  接管华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street! Takeover! Wall Street!
所以他把包丢在一边就走了
So he ditches it and keeps moving.
你能想象妈妈会是什么表情吗
Could you imagine the look on mom's face?
-嘭  -靠
- Bam. - Damn it!
他们不小心撞到
They bump into each other,
这一幕恰巧被咖啡卡车旁的
drawing the attention of the street drummer
街鼓手看到
who's now by the coffee truck.
你所拨打的电话
The subscriber you're trying
暂时未能接通
to reach is not available--
他太迟了
He's too late.
兄弟  故事不错
Well, that's a nice story, bro,
但仍然不能告诉我们杰西的同伙是谁
but it still doesn't tell us who Jesse's partner is.
肯定是炸弹爆炸前
Well, it's gotta be whoever Jesse was on the phone with
同杰西通电话的人
in the minutes before the bomb went off.
第一通来电通话多久
How long was that first incoming call?
八秒
Uh, eight seconds.
所以有可能是说"准备就绪"之类的话
So that was probably the "All systems go" Call.
然而在背包被偷后
Then after the backpack was stolen,
杰西试图告诉同伙"一切尚未就绪"
Jesse tried to make an "All systems not go" Call,
可他没来得及
but he didn't get through in time.
有目击者记得
Do any of the witnesses remember
杰西是和谁一起去的吗
who Jesse was hanging out with?
没有  但我们在根据他朋友的叙述
Not yet, but we're still reconstructing his movements
重组他的一举一动
based on statements from his friends--
贝多芬T恤
A Beethoven T-shirt.
电话  应答
A call-and-response.
我知道杰西的同伙是谁了
I know who Jesse's partner is.
接管华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street!
鲍比说在他偷背包之前
Bobby remembered hearing a Beethoven ringtone
听到附近响起
coming from nearby
贝多芬曲子的铃声
just before he stole the backpack.
同时西区瓦利也说过
And West Side Wally said
贝多芬出现
Beethoven showed up,
演奏其著名的"第五交响曲"
conducting his "Fifth Symphony."
准备好了
We're good to go.
就在那时穿着贝多芬T恤
That was actually Jesse Friedman
以贝多芬曲子作铃声的杰西·弗里德曼
with his Beethoven T-shirt and ringtone,
打了那通"准备就绪"的电话
making his "All systems go" Call.
准备好了
We're good to go.
我们知道他在和100英尺范围内的人通话
We know he was talking to someone within 100 feet
且通话时间八秒
and that call lasted eight seconds.
足够双方应答
Long enough for a call-and-response--
这个应答的人
A call-and-response to the one person
能够让爆炸经过在电视直播中呈现
who could broadcast the explosion live on television
给公众带来活动所需要的震撼
and bring the publicity that the movement needed.
准备好了
We're good to go.
收到
Roger that.
准备
Live in...
三
Three...
我现在在博亦伦广场
I'm here at Boylan Plaza on day 36
现在是占领抗议的第36天
of the Takeover! Protest.
接电话的就是琳安·韦斯特
Leann West was on the other end of that phone.
接管华尔街
Takeover! Wall Street!
收到
Roger that.
不  我没有
No, I wasn't.
我没和任何人通话
I wasn't on the phone with anyone.
我是在和摄影师讲话
I was talking to my cameraman.
我已经向联调局说了整个经过
I already told the FBI the whole story.
不过你漏掉了些细节
Yeah, except you left out a few details.
比如你认识杰西·弗里德曼
Like the fact that you knew Jesse Friedman.
你们是哈德逊大学的校友
The two of you went to Hudson University.
对  很多人都是啊
Yeah, so did a lot of people.
我们猜想你们在抗议活动中重遇
We're guessing the two of you reunited at the protest.
一起喝东西叙旧  然后你想到一计
You went out for drinks and you hatched a plan.
他想让抗议活动得到媒体关注
He wanted media attention for the movement.
而你想晋升到主播台
You wanted to get promoted to the anchor desk.
所以你将摄影机摆到最好的拍摄角度
So you set up your cameras at the perfect vantage point.
当你开始直播时
You waited until you went live
就引爆了炸弹
and you detonated that bomb.
什么
What?
神经
That is insane.
这太荒谬了
This is ridiculous,
我不想再听下去了
and I will not listen to another word of it.
我们到此为止
We're done here.
还认得吗
Do you recognize that?
你打给杰西时用的一次性手机
That's the burner cell that you used to call Jesse.
我们在博亦伦广场两个街区外的
Found it in a storm drain
下水沟找到的
about two blocks from Boylan Plaza.
知道我们还找到什么了吗
You know what else we found in there?
你用来远程引爆炸弹的遥控器
The remote you used to detonate the bomb.
小得足够你藏在手中
Small enough to hide in the palm of your hand.
琳安  上面都是你的指纹
It's got your fingerprints all over it, Leann.
你们怎么找到的
How did you find that?
用你手机的GPS导航系统
By tracking your movements after the explosion
追踪爆炸后你的活动路线
using your phone's GPS.
我没想过伤害他人的
No one was supposed to get hurt.
我只想单纯制造些响声
It was just gonna make a lot of noise,
那样人们就会开始关注我这个播报员
and people would start respecting me as a reporter,
但所有事都偏离轨道了
but everything just went wrong.
那在你意识到自己的所为之后
Why didn't you come forward
为什么没有站出来承担一切
once you realized what you had done?
我考虑过的
I thought about it,
可那能帮到什么呢
but what good would that do?
我为杰西保密
I kept quiet for Jesse.
我不想毁了他的声誉
I wanted to protect his memory.
那就是你朋友杰西所说的
Well, that's what your friend Jesse would call
沉默即是犯罪
sinning by silence.
并非明智之举
It's not smart.
一点都不勇敢
It's not brave.
只是怯弱罢了
It's just cowardly.
联邦调查局已逮捕琳安·韦斯特
The FBI has taken Leann West into custody.
她为了满足其盲目的野心
This woman, whose blind ambition
致使五人无辜丧命
led to the death of five people,
她将受到其应有的惩罚
will get what she deserves.
我
I, um...
我要谢谢你们每个人
I want to thank each of you
为这个案子所做的一切
for what you did to make this happen.
你们
You, uh...
都付出了百分之一百一的心血
All put in 110%,
我深感自豪
Made me proud.
我们现在
So let's, uh...
散会  赶紧回家
get outta here, head on home,
好好休息
and catch up on some much-needed rest.
我还是有点烦躁不安
You know what? I'm still kind of wired.
要一起去喝杯东西吗
Do you guys want to go out for a drink?
抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
我太想珍妮了  一日不见如隔三秋
You know, it feels like a month since I've seen Jenny.
-我得回家去  -我也是
- I should really get home. - Me, too.
我醉了肯定会对你大发牢骚的
I'm tanked. I'll holler at you.
所以就我们俩去了
So I guess it's just us.
嗯
Yeah.
现在案子结束了
You know, now that the case is done...
你想跟我说什么来着
What did you want to talk about?
没什么
Nothing.
不是什么重要的事
Nothing important anyway.
我回家了
I'm gonna head home.
晚安
Night.
Good night.